<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" media="screen" href="/~d/styles/atom10full.xsl"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" media="screen" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~d/styles/itemcontent.css"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:feedburner="http://rssnamespace.org/feedburner/ext/1.0">
    <title type="text">RIABiz</title>
    <subtitle type="html">Exceptional values, exceptional practices.</subtitle>
		
		<updated>2011-02-25T15:12:31-07:00</updated>
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
		
    <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:main</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" href="http://www.riabiz.com?subscribed=true" />
    
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2009, RIABiz</rights>

    <generator uri="http://www.riabiz.com" version="1">
        RIABiz
    </generator>

    
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://feeds.feedburner.com/riabiz" /><feedburner:info uri="riabiz" /><atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="hub" href="http://pubsubhubbub.appspot.com/" /><entry>
        <title>Pershing warns IBDs to embrace hybrid business model or risk being marginalized</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/riabiz/~3/Xd0ARGmsQxU/5757001" />

        <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:25-02-2011:5757001</id>

        <updated>2011-02-26T11:05:04-07:00</updated>
        <published>2011-02-25T07:12:31-07:00</published>

        <author>
            <name>elizabeth.macbride5</name>
            <uri>http://www.riabiz.com</uri>
        </author>

        <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en" xml:base=""><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
								<h3>Schwab gives hybrid advisors another vote of confidence in its own new study yesterday </h3><br />
								
								<p style="display:block; float:left; padding: 0 10px 10px 0; width:200px;"><a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5757001?subscribed=true"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5778043/b" class="article-image" /></a><br />
								<small>Jim Roth says that the economic of the IBD business have shifted to make a hybrid model a necessity for IBDs.</small></p>
								
								
										<p>Independent broker-dealers should pull out the stops to embrace a model of serving the growing army of hybrid advisors, according to Pershing <span class="caps">LLC</span>, which gave RIABiz a glimpse at a white paper on hybrid advisors that will be released in a few weeks. </p>

	<p>The Jersey City giant of <span class="caps">IBD</span> clearing had always treated the approach of these advisors  — who have one foot in the world of commissions and the other in the world of fees — as a viable option. Now, it has taken a more definitive stand based on its new study. </p>

	<p>The findings of the report, “The Economics of Constructing a Hybrid Platform,” show that IBDs will be better able to support the model because registered reps are – in an era of increasing regulatory scrutiny and complexity – much more comfortable with paying a custody fee for the <span class="caps">RIA</span> assets.</p>
									<span id="jump" />

	<h2>Loss leader</h2>

	<p>For many broker-dealers, oversight of those fee-based assets traditionally has been a bit of a loss leader to pave the way  for handling the hybrid advisors’ transactional business. (See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5438244" target="_new">Nine things I learned as an <span class="caps">RIA</span> infiltrator in an <span class="caps">IBD</span> world</a>.)</p>

	<p>The low or nonexistent profit margins made supporting the model more marginal — but that has changed.</p>

	<p>“Independent broker-dealers who choose to ignore the movement to advisory and hybrid models may see their growth marginalized. ...The hybrid model represents an opportunity for broker-dealers to grow and compete in the next decade and beyond,” Pershing’s report says. It goes on to say that of the more than 1,200 IBDs, those who use a hybrid strategy will boost their ability to grow and improve their ability to recruit advisors.</p>

	<p>The new stance by Pershing arrives virtually at the same time that <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/70050" target="_new">Schwab Advisor Services</a> has issued its own report on the burgeoning hybrid market, a report in which the largest custodian for independent RIAs takes a few more steps toward embracing the hybrid business model.</p>

	<p>Taken together, the two reports indicate a shift in the marketplace. Where hybrid advisors have been seen by many companies as inhabiting a strange in-between zone, the hybrid model is developing into a viable long-term business.</p>

	<p>“For awhile it looked like the hybrid model was a holding pattern but now we’re seeing that as the regulatory burden continues to grow, hybrid will be the legitimate destination for people,” said Eric Schwartz, chief executive officer of <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/70070" target="_new">Cambridge Investment Research</a>. </p>

	<p>Cambridge, of Fairfield, Ohio, is among the few independent broker-dealers to have built a business model embracing hybrid advisors. About 90% of the firm’s 1,900 advisors use commission-based and fee-based model, said Schwartz.</p>

	<p>See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/107150" target="_new">5 Reasons why the hybrid <span class="caps">RIA</span> model may be a bigger deal than ever</a>.</p>

	<p>The welcoming attitude of companies such as Cambridge, First Allied and Capital Analysts may spread to other IBDs as the economics of the business evolve, Roth said. That trio of IBDs generally has offered custody services for free. See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/6015" target="_new">Two Broker-dealers pick Pershing for ...</a></p>
									<a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5757001?subscribed=true" class="readmore">Read More</a><br />
								
            <xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/riabiz/~4/Xd0ARGmsQxU" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.riabiz.com/a/5757001?subscribed=true</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Mark Palmer departs Cetera and joins big West Coast RIA</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/riabiz/~3/Us0rgy_Szco/5763001" />

        <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:25-02-2011:5763001</id>

        <updated>2011-02-26T11:51:15-07:00</updated>
        <published>2011-02-25T07:01:18-07:00</published>

        <author>
            <name>BrookeSouthall</name>
            <uri>http://www.riabiz.com</uri>
        </author>

        <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en" xml:base=""><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
								<h3>Presidio Financial Partners knew the veteran from his Schwab days and lured him back to San Francisco</h3><br />
								
								<p style="display:block; float:left; padding: 0 10px 10px 0; width:200px;"><a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5763001?subscribed=true"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5774163/b" class="article-image" /></a><br />
								<small>Mark Palmer will manage aggressive growth plans for Presidio Financial Partners LLC.</small></p>
								
								
										<p>Mark R. Palmer, who was Cetera’s national sales director, has left the company to take over management of one of the largest RIAs on the West Coast.</p>

	<p>Palmer, who was also a former Schwab managing director, is now the head of wealth management for Presidio Financial Partners <span class="caps">LLC</span>, which manages more than $4 billion of assets from San Francisco. <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/4772120" target="_new">Cetera Financial Group</a> is the Los Angeles-based umbrella for Financial Network Investment Corp., Multi Financial Securities Corp., and PrimeVest Financial Services Inc.</p>

	<p>Palmer, 45, is taking on the newly created role to help handle the day-to-day efforts required to execute the ambitious national plan for growth. The wealth management arm of Presidio has 34 employees including 12 advisors. The rest are client service and operations staff. Presidio also has an investment banking side, which brings its total headcount to 60.</p>
									<span id="jump" />

	<p>The company already has offices in Los Angeles, Dallas and San Francisco. It has one advisor in Chicago and plans a formal office there. It is also eyeing an expansion to New York City.</p>

	<p>“We have clients on the Eastern Seaboard that might take us there,” Palmer says.</p>

	<h2>M&amp;A-minded</h2>

	<p>For now Palmer, a Presidio managing director, plans to concentrate developing systems and processes that will make scaling the business easier. He also believes he will next be busy recruiting wealth managers to the firm and looking for possible acquisitions over the next three to five years.</p>

	<p>“We’ve worked with Mark closely and were always impressed by his extensive knowledge of the industry and best practices in firm management, as well as by his professionalism,” said Brodie L. Cobb, Presidio’s managing director, <span class="caps">CEO</span> and founder in a release. “We need a strong leader to achieve the aggressive growth goals we have for wealth management group and are confident Mark will more than meet them.”</p>

	<p>For quotes from Palmer from his Schwab consulting days, see: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/13001" target="_new">Schwab study shatters three <span class="caps">RIA</span> myths</a>.</p>

	<p>In his role as managing director, business consulting at Schwab, he worked with big firms like Presidio in charting and executing strategy.</p>

	<p>Presidio’s wealth management arm was originally just an effort to serve investment banking clients dissatisfied with their choices after cashing out of their venture. It has now become the focus of the company but it still focuses on first generation wealth and so-called serial entrepreneurs looking both to have assets managed — and capital and expertise for their next deal.</p>

	<p>In August of 2010, Palmer left Schwab for Cetera in El Segundo, Calif. He joined Presidio by November. See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/2045005" target="_new">Cetera finds talent again at Schwab to fill national sales director position</a>.</p>

	<p>Cetera has been on a tear hiring top talent from around the <span class="caps">RIA</span> and <span class="caps">IBD</span> world. <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/4772120" target="_new">Cetera Financial Group</a> is financed by deep-pocketed Lightyear, a private equity firm that has invested $3 billion only in financial services companies and is run by former Paine Webber <span class="caps">CEO</span> amd <span class="caps">UBS</span> U.S. chairman, Donald Marron. </p>

	<p>See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/1804008" target="_new">Cetera ...</a></p>
									<a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5763001?subscribed=true" class="readmore">Read More</a><br />
								
            <xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/riabiz/~4/Us0rgy_Szco" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.riabiz.com/a/5763001?subscribed=true</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>What one advisor's letter to her son reveals about Americans' attitudes toward money</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/riabiz/~3/KLMkvqZWvfQ/5591227" />

        <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:16-02-2011:5591227</id>

        <updated>2011-02-26T07:35:47-07:00</updated>
        <published>2011-02-25T06:56:49-07:00</published>

        <author>
            <name>elizabeth.macbride5</name>
            <uri>http://www.riabiz.com</uri>
        </author>

        <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en" xml:base=""><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
								<h3>The financial crisis may have opened the door to money-talk -- and raises questions about advisors' responsibilities</h3><br />
								
								<p style="display:block; float:left; padding: 0 10px 10px 0; width:200px;"><a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5591227?subscribed=true"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5742210/b" class="article-image" /></a><br />
								<small>Karin Maloney Stifler: Talking about money really is our last taboo subject.</small></p>
								
								
										<p><em>Elizabeth’s note: This story by Bob Margolis was written before he died early last month. I edited it without his help; I take responsibility for any mistakes in it. With his parent’s permission, we decided to run it. Using a letter that some of you may remember from last year as a jumping off point, the story explores American’s attitudes toward money and advisors responsibilities toward Americans. Recognizing that more advisors are seizing the opportunity to donate their services to help people learn about financial responsibility, at the end of this story, I’ve listed a few organizations that give opportunities for advisors to volunteer. Here is RIABiz’s story about Bob Margolis: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5368493" target="_new">Goodbye to Bob Margolis, true friend of independent advisors</a>. We’re still missing his e-mails and calls — one of the last of which pointed out that there really is a “Stifler’s mom” — a reference to particularly crass movie called American Pie.</em></p>

	<p>Fame came crashing into Karin Maloney Stifler’s reality last Labor Day. That happens when the “Grey Lady” runs a letter you wrote to your son Colin on the eve of his departure for college.</p>

	<p>Last Aug. 30, The New York Times printed “Letter To My College Bound Son,” in which the founder of Ohio-based True Wealth Advisors speaks openly to her son about among other things, fiscal responsibility and in essence, has the crucial “money talk.” </p>
									<span id="jump" />

	<blockquote>
		<p>Reaching agreement about what to expect from each other is one of the most important ways we have prepared for this life transition. Putting things in writing is sometimes more powerful than speaking the words. So here it is.  Let’s both promise to keep our word.<br />What you can expect from us:</p>
	</blockquote>

	<blockquote>
		<p>– Our love and moral support. – Financial support in the ways we have discussed. – Respect. – Room to grow — no helicopter parenting. – Won’t change your bedroom (at least for now).</p>
	</blockquote>

	<blockquote>
		<p>What we can expect from you:</p>
	</blockquote>

	<blockquote>
		<p>Your Job: – Value and appreciate this investment in your personal growth and your future …</p>
	</blockquote>

	<blockquote>
		<p>Your Money: – Give yourself a weekly allowance and stick to it._– Pay with cash or debit card.– Use your credit card for emergencies in the ways we have discussed. – Check your bank account online at least once a week. – Monitor automatic banking texts and e-mail alerts. – Don’t lend or borrow money from friends. – Protect your valuables – most of all, your identity. – If you lose or break something, replace it at your own expense.</p>
	</blockquote>

<p />

	<p>This communication between mother and son seems so logical, helpful and obvious. Yet, according to advisors across the board, these conversations rarely take place between family members, friends and associates.</p>

	<p>Stifler’s letter, which was forwarded, reblogged and commented on, has continued to resonate. You can see the full text of her letter on the Financial Planning Association’s <a href="http://blog.fpaforfinancialplanning.org/2010/08/26/a-letter-to-my-college-bound-son" target="_new">blog</a>.</p>

	<p>“The response to the letter was much more than I expected. Especially when it kinda went viral. Colin lives with three others, including one guy who is a news hound. He found it and thought it was cool,” explains Stifler. As the former Pro Bono chair of the <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/107075" target="_new">Financial Planning Association</a>, she is no stranger to having these talks both with clients and those who lack the means to work with a financial advisor. “Why is it that every time we need to say something meaningful we go and get a Hallmark card? Talking about money really is our last taboo subject. So I hope my letter to Colin can serve as an outline ...</p>
									<a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5591227?subscribed=true" class="readmore">Read More</a><br />
								
            <xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/riabiz/~4/KLMkvqZWvfQ" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.riabiz.com/a/5591227?subscribed=true</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>Merrill Lynch and Bank of America cultural tension may spin out a new round of breakaways, recruiters say</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/riabiz/~3/UmfzbucQaXc/5732006" />

        <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:24-02-2011:5732006</id>

        <updated>2011-02-25T18:01:27-07:00</updated>
        <published>2011-02-24T07:36:40-07:00</published>

        <author>
            <name>BrookeSouthall</name>
            <uri>http://www.riabiz.com</uri>
        </author>

        <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en" xml:base=""><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
								<h3>A big Maine team goes to HighTower; more Merrill brokers in pipeline, says Weissbluth</h3><br />
								
								<p style="display:block; float:left; padding: 0 10px 10px 0; width:200px;"><a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5732006?subscribed=true"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5738002/b" class="article-image" /></a><br />
								<small>Ed Simmons has a doctorate from Harvard and a 24-year tenure with Merrill Lynch. He became an RIA on Friday.</small></p>
								
								
										<p><em>Brooke’s Note: I took special note of this Merrill Lynch breakaway because it was the first such news I’d encountered in the place (Greater Portland, Maine) where I was born and grew up. It’s a place where the lobster boats rev in the background, tourists putter quaint shops and the salt air is palpable on the breeze. I was ready to work in thoughts about my first career as a clam digger. My reporting led me in a different direction. The Simmons Wilkes breakaway spawned sharp thoughts from experts about what it says about where Merrill Lynch stands two years after it got gobbled up by Bank of America.</em></p>

	<p>A seven-person advisory team managing $550 million broke away from Merrill Lynch in Portland, Maine, to join HighTower Advisors on Friday.</p>

	<p>The team, Simmons Wilkes Investment Advisors, extends HighTower’s reach to the largest city Down East. The advisors declined to be interviewed. HighTower says they are too busy setting up shop to take phone calls.</p>
									<span id="jump" />

	<p>HighTower’s <span class="caps">CEO</span> said the Simmons Wilkes breakaway was evidence that a long-predicted surge of Merrill breakaways after the wirehouse’s acquisition by Bank of America might finally be materializing.</p>

	<h2>Increased interest</h2>

	<p>“What we’re seeing is an increased interest from Merrill Lynch advisors because of the cultural tensions of Merrill Lynch and Bank of America,” said Elliot Weissbluth. HighTower Advisors is a Chicago-based serial buyer of RIAs and wirehouse brokerage teams. HighTower historically has recruited predominantly from <span class="caps">UBS</span> and Morgan Stanley Smith Barney. See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/869002" target="_new">HighTower doubles recruiting staff and seeks green pastures of Morgan Stanley Smith Barney brokers</a>.</p>

	<p>A couple of recruiters agreed there is more interest from Merrill advisors now – though whether that translates into big numbers of breakaways is a question mark.</p>

	<p>Mindy Diamond, <span class="caps">CEO</span> of <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/2081011" target="_new">Diamond Consultants</a> in Chester, N.J., indicates that BofA may have added get-out-while-the getting-is-good fuel to the breakaway fire with its announcement that U.S. Trust advisors must give a 60-day notice before leaving — and refrain from soliciting clients for an additional eight months. Merrill brokers may be worried that the parent company might apply the same rule to them.</p>

	<p>The cooling off period is known on Wall Street as a garden leave. U.S. Trust had 2,274 advisors as of Dec. 31.</p>

	<p>U.S. Trust’s decision followed the loss of its top advisor, Mike Brown, to Dynasty Financial Partners and the settlement of a legal case on the matter. See: <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/4791036" target="_new">Bank of America throws a legal wrench at big wealth management start-up</a> Dynasty plans to keep the $5.9 billion of assets Brown brought with him with <a href="http://www.riabiz.com/d/70049" target="_new">Fidelity Institutional Wealth Services</a>. </p>

	<p><span class="image-and-caption textile-generated" style="width:auto;float:right;display:block;padding:0;margin:0 0 10px 15px;"><span class="image textile-generated"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5738003/b" title="Gibson Wilkes has been with Dean Witter and A.G. Edwards in addition to Merrill Lynch but has settled on her own RIA practice." alt="Gibson Wilkes has been with Dean Witter and A.G. Edwards in addition to Merrill Lynch but has settled on her own RIA practice." /></span><br /><span class="image-caption textile-generated"><small>Gibson Wilkes has been with Dean <br />Witter and A.G. Edwards in addition <br />to Merrill Lynch but has settled <br />on her own <span class="caps">RIA</span> practice. </small></span></span></p>

	<h2>Internal chatter</h2>

	<p>“I have spoken with a number of Merrill advisors since Thursday when this was announced and the internal chatter is all about concern that if B of A did this to the U.S. Trust advisors, what’s to stop them from attempting the same with the Merrill ones,” Diamond said ...</p>
									<a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5732006?subscribed=true" class="readmore">Read More</a><br />
								
            <xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/riabiz/~4/UmfzbucQaXc" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.riabiz.com/a/5732006?subscribed=true</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    
    <entry>
        <title>When to fire an investment manager</title>
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/riabiz/~3/9eYiQs8spuY/5742002" />

        <id>tag:riabiz.com,2009:24-02-2011:5742002</id>

        <updated>2011-02-24T12:03:11-07:00</updated>
        <published>2011-02-24T07:35:12-07:00</published>

        <author>
            <name>elizabeth.macbride5</name>
            <uri>http://www.riabiz.com</uri>
        </author>

        <content type="xhtml" xml:lang="en" xml:base=""><div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
								<h3>Like selling a beaten down stock, it shouldn't be viewed as an admission of failure</h3><br />
								
								<p style="display:block; float:left; padding: 0 10px 10px 0; width:200px;"><a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5742002?subscribed=true"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5748003/b" class="article-image" /></a><br />
								<small>Jolie Keller: Knowing when to terminate a manager or not usually isn’t a clean, straightforward decision; rather, a picture emerges or a case develops over time.</small></p>
								
								
										<p><em>“When to fire an investment manager,” by Jolie Keller, Rick Iwanski and Barry K. Mendelson, was originally published in Investment Management Consultants Association’s January/February 2011 issue of Investments &amp; Wealth Monitor. To access more articles,</em> visit: <a href="http://www.IMCA.org" target="_new">IMCA’s Web site</a></p>

	<p>Knowing when to fire a manager is a complex professional decision. A number of factors beyond the mere analysis of past returns need to be taken into account so that a “case” builds for termination. Whatever model you rely upon, it is important that you have a process incorporated into your practice procedure to handle this inevitable event.</p>

	<h2>Background</h2>

	<p>Knowing when to fire an investment manager (1) always will be a difficult decision and requires a professional judgment call. Firing a manager is to some extent an admission of failure, and our emotions can play havoc in such situations. It’s important to get beyond this very human response by making sure you have a process in place at your practice for terminating managers. In our practice, we do not believe in a cookie-cutter, purely returns-driven termination method—even though, at times, relative performance or lack thereof is the dominant factor in this decision. It is important to remember that inputs to the firing decision are usually multi-factor, at times non-quantitative, and don’t necessarily reveal themselves all at once, so it is reasonable to expect some variation in approach among practitioners.</p>
									<span id="jump" />

	<p>Knowing when to terminate a manager is somewhat analogous to knowing when to sell a stock. Just as you rely on your investment managers to have and execute a sell discipline in your client’s portfolio, you should have guidelines that you rely upon to help you know when a manager is entering the “firing zone.” It can be difficult to pull the trigger for lots of reasons (i.e., taxes, operational challenges, relationships with managers, etc.) even when the facts indicate that firing is prudent. Vigilance and impartiality in observing your self-imposed guidelines are prerequisite. We have found that, even though we are not always right from a purely after-the-fact performance standpoint, it is better to be safe than sorry. It is always better to have a prudent process in place than none at all.</p>

	<p><span class="image-and-caption textile-generated" style="width:auto;float:right;display:block;padding:0;margin:0 0 10px 15px;"><span class="image textile-generated"><img src="http://www.riabiz.com/i/5734004/b" title="Rick Iwanski" alt="Rick Iwanski" /></span><br /><span class="image-caption textile-generated"><small>Rick Iwanski </small></span></span></p>

	<p>What follows are thoughts of practitioners who exclusively perform manager due diligence. Knowing when to terminate a manager or not usually isn’t a clean, straightforward decision; rather, a picture emerges or a case develops over time. Here’s some advice you can use in your practice to sharpen this part of your skill set.</p>

	<h2>Chief Termination Factors</h2>

	<p>The chief factors on our radar screen when considering the need for firing a manager include the following:</p>

	<p><strong>Organizational stability</strong></p>

	<p>The principal assets of any money management firm are people—especially the investment professionals. You want to know whether they are highly motivated to manage your clients’ money. To find out, it’s necessary to identify the key people to whom you can attribute the portfolio’s track record. Changes in this group or the organization often can disrupt the investment process, and you should stay aware of changes that could negatively impact portfolio decisions such as the following:</p>

	<p>•	Employee turnover, especially departures of firm leaders and key investment professionals such as portfolio managers and valued analysts (whether they work on the portfolio strategy you are using or not)</p>

	<p>•	Changes in ownership or control of a money management firm’s equity, which can influence power and the personal satisfaction of employees</p>

	<p>•	Leadership changes or ...</p>
									<a href="http://www.riabiz.com/a/5742002?subscribed=true" class="readmore">Read More</a><br />
								
            <xhtml:img xmlns:xhtml="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" src="http://feeds.feedburner.com/~r/riabiz/~4/9eYiQs8spuY" height="1" width="1" /></div></content>
    <feedburner:origLink>http://www.riabiz.com/a/5742002?subscribed=true</feedburner:origLink></entry>
    

</feed>
